Register of the Valerian Ivanovich Moravskii Papers, 1917-1937.
Hoover Institution Archives
- Correspondence., 1921-1937.
  - Chertkov, G.I.
    - Sazonov, A.V.
      - 1926, Feb.-Dec. (Folder 14)
    - Zenkevich, S.I., Jan. 1935 (Folder 15)
  - Douglas, D.K. (Folder 16)
    - Moravskii, V.I.,Nov. 1931- Aug. 1936
  - Druzhylovskii, A.D. (Folder 17)
    - Vasiliev, B.P., Nov. 1922
  - Fortunatov, E.A. (Folder 18)
    - Vasiliev-Dubrovskii, A.N., Oct. 1922
  - Gerasimov, I.I.
    - Levchatkin-Atkins, S.V., Jan. 1933 (Folder 19)
    - Moravskii, V.I., Dec. 1932-Jan. 1933 (Folder 20)
  - Gol'dshtein, A.A. (Folder 21)
    - Sazonov, A.V., Nov. 1922
  - Golovachev, M.P.
    - Chertkov, G.I., Oct. 1927 (Folder 22)
    - Khorvat, D.L., Nov. 1927 (Folder 23)
    - Moravskii, V.I., June 1922-Dec. 1927 (Folder 24)
    - Sazonov, A.V., Nov. 1923-Feb. 1927 (Folder 25)
    - Tanaka, Baron, Apr. 1927 (Folder 26)
    - Tsizidantsy, 1927 (Folder 27)
    - Vasiliev, B.P., Jan. 1923 (Folder 28)
    - X., letter to M.P. Golovachev, Oct. 1927 (Folder 29)
  - Golovacheva, O.S. (Folder 30)
    - Moravskii, V.I., May 1922-May 1923
  - Gondatti, N.L.
    - I.A., June 1932 (Folder 31)
    - Moravskii, V.I., Aug. 1932-March 1933 (Folder 32)
    - Vladislavtsev, June 1932 (Folder 33)
  - Gryzov, A.G.
    - Golovachev, M.P., Nov. 1922 (Folder 34)
    - Sazonov, A.V., Nov. 1922-Nov. 1925 (Folder 35)
  - Gushchin, A.F. (Folder 36)
    - Moravskii, V.I., May 1928
  - Hessen, I.V. (Folder 37)
    - Moravskii,V.I., May 1924
  - IAkovkin, M.I.
    - Levchatkin-Atkins S.V., Apr. 1933 (Folder 38)
    - Moravskii, V.I., Feb.-Oct. 1933 (Folder 39)
  - IAkushev, I.A.
    - Moravskii, V.I., March 1925-March 1933 (Folder 40)
    - Purin, A.A., Aug. 1929-Sept. 1930 (Folder 41)
  - Innokentii, B. (Folder 42)
    - Sazonov, A.V., July-April 1922
  - Ivanov-Rynov, P.P. (Folder 43)
    - Moravskii, V.I., March-July 1925
  - Kalashnikov, N.S.
    - Moravskii, V.I., Dec. 1922-Sept. 1927 (Folder 44)
    - Sazonov, A.V., March 1924-Oct.1925 (Folder 45)
  - Kalinin, N.V.
    - Moravskii, V.I., June 1930- Nov. 1932 (Folder 46)
    - Sazonov, A.V., July 1921 (Folder 47)
  - Kapnitsa, B. (Folder 48)
    - Cherednichenko-Mersie, V.P., n.d.
  - Kartushevich, M. (Folder 49)
    - Moravskii, V.I., June 1933
  - KHanzhin, M. (Folder 50)
    - Balakin, A.V., Aug. 1926
  - KHorvat, D.L. (Box 9)
    - Chertkov, G.I., Jan.-Feb. 1930 (Folder l)
    - KHorvat, D.D., Dec. 1928 (Folder 2)
    - Moravskii, V.I., Aug. 1928 (Folder 3)
  - KHreshchatitskii, B. (Folder 4)
    - Moravskii, V.I., Apr. 1924
  - Krivoruchko, M.G. (Folder 5)
    - Moravskii,V.I., 1932-1938
  - Larionov (Folder 6)
    - Moravskii, V.I., May 1928
  - Lavrov, I.A. (Folder 7)
    - Moravskii, V.I., Jan.-Nov. 1933
  - Lebedev, D.A. (Folder 8)
    - Moravskii, V.I., Feb. 1924
  - Levchatkin-Atkins,S.V.
    - Chertkov, G.I., Aug. 1931-Oct. 1934 (Folder 9)
    - Consul-General of Great Britain, May 1933 (Folder 10)
    - Gerasimov, N.I., Jan. 1932 (Folder 11)
    - Kalinin, N.V., June-Nov. 1931 (Folder 12)
    - Liapustin, M.S., March 1933 (Folder 13)
    - Moravskii, V.I., Feb. 1935-June 1937 (Folder 14)
  - Liapustin, M.S.
    - Levchatkin-Atkins, S.V., March 1933 (Folder 15)
    - Moravskii, V.I., April-June 1933 (Folder 16)
  - Liudmilov, A. (Folder 17)
    - Moravskii, V.I., Feb. 1929
  - Lovtsov, K.
    - Balakin, A.V., Sept. 1926 (Folder 18)
  - Malinovskii, N.P. (Folder 19)
    - Moravskii, V.I., May-July 1927
  - Marinich, N.
    - Marinich, N.I., Jan. 1929 (Folder 20)
    - Moravskii, V.I., March 1932 (Folder 21)
    - Newman, D.F., 1929 (Folder 22)
  - Mazitov, Z.S. (Folder 23)
    - Moravskii, V.I., March 1938-May 1935
  - Mefodii, Archbishop of Kharbin and Manchuria (Folder 24)
    - Golovachev, M.P., Feb., May 1927
  - Meibom, F. (Folder 25)
    - Sazonov, A.V., Feb.-May 1923
  - Miatelitsyna (Folder 26)
    - Moravskii, V.I., Dec. 1929
  - Moravskii, V.I.
    - Borisov, M.I., Aug. 1932 (Folder 27)
    - Cherednichenko-Mersie, V.P., Apr. 1926 (Folder 28)
    - Chertkov, G.I.
      - 1927 (Folder 29)
      - 1931 (Folder 30)
      - 1932 (Folder 31)
      - 1935 (Folder 32)
    - Elliott, Sir Charles, Aug. 1927 (Folder 33)
    - Graves, Gen. W., May 1923 (Folder 34)
    - IAkushev, I.A., May 1931-1934 (Folder 35)
    - Kalinin, N.V., Sept. 1930-June 1931 (Folder 36)
    - Levchatkin-Atkins, S.V., Aug. 1932-May 1934 (Folder 37)
    - P.P.P., May 1934 (Folder 38)
    - Purin, A.A., May 1929 (Folder 39)
    - Sazonov, A.V., Nov. 1923-Nov. 1926 (Folder 40)
    - Vladislavtsev, I.A., 1932 (Folder 41)
    - Miscellaneous unsigned letters to V.I. Moravskii, 1927-1928 (Folder 42)
    - Telegrams and postcards to V.I. Moravskii in Japanese, n.d. (Folder 43)
  - Mretskii, V. IA. (Folder 44)
    - Moravskii, V.I., Jan. 1929-Oct.1932
  - Nikitin, N. (Folder 45)
    - Moravskii, V.I., March 1923
  - Ogloblin, P.P. (Folder 46)
    - Moravskii, V.I., April 1933
  - Petrov (Folder 47)
    - Balakin, A.V., Sept. 1926
  - Popov, I.I. (Folder 48)
    - Sazonov, A.V., Nov. 1922-July 1923
  - Puchkov, F.A. (Folder 49)
    - Golovachev, M.P., Oct. 1923
  - Purin, A.A.
    - Chertkov, G.I., July 1929 (Folder 50)
    - Moravskii, V.I., Dec. 1928-Feb. 1930 (Folder 51)
    - Zaitsev, P.I., Jan. 1929 (Folder 52)
  - Rafalov, R. (Babushkin-Rafalov, R.) (Folder 53)
    - Moravskii, V.I., 1928
  - Romanovskii, IU. (Folder 54)
    - Borisov, M.I., Feb.-Aug. 1932
  - Rybakov, V. (Folder 55)
    - Moravskii, V.I., June, 1925
  - Satorskii-Rzhevskii, Count (Folder 56)
    - Moravskii, V.I., July 1926
  - Sazonov, A.V.
    - Agapov, E.M., Nov. 1923-Nov. 1926 (Folder 57)
    - Aleksandr Stepanovich, Feb. 1926 (Folder 58)
    - Balakin, A.V., (includes letter from M.P. Golovachev re A.V. Balakin), 1926 (Folder 59)
    - Burtsev, V.L., Apr.-May 1923 (Folder 60)
    - Chertkov, G.I., Dec. 1923-Sept. 1926 (Folder 61)
    - Golovachev, M.P., Dec. 1922-Sept. 1925 (Folder 62)
    - Gryzov, May-Nov. 1924 (Folder 63)
    - Kalashnikov, N.S., 1922-Feb. 1936 (Folder 64)
    - Kalinin, N.V., Nov. 1923 (Folder 65)
    - Ivanov-Rinov, P.P., May 1923 (Box 10, Folder l)
    - Matsumoto, Sept. 1925 (Folder 2)
    - Moravskii, V.I., March-May 1926 (Folder 3)
    - Popov, I.I., Apr.-Nov. 1923 (Folder 4)
    - Sergei Nikolaevich, May 1924 (Folder 5)
    - Shevchenko, M.F., Feb. 1924-March 1925 (Folder 6)
    - Vasilii Vladimirovich, March 1924 (Folder 7)
    - Vishnevskii, E.K., March-Dec. 1924 (Folder 8)
    - Miscellaneous, Nov. 1924-Apr. 1928 (Folder 9)
    - Personal correspondence with family in Soviet Union, n.d. (Folder 10)
    - Letters to A.V. Sazonov, 1921-1928 (Folder 11)
  - Sedlitskii, I.V. (Folder 12)
    - Moravskii, V.I., March, 1932
  - Shamgulov, M.A. (Folder 13)
    - Moravskii, V.I., Aug. 1926-June 1931
  - Shadrin, M.A. (Folder 14)
    - Sosnovskii, A.S., Dec. 1924
  - Shevchenko, M.F. (Folder 15)
    - Sazonov, A.V., March 1921-May 1924
  - Shliapnikov, S. (Folder 16)
    - Sazonov, A.V., Apr. 1924
  - Shneir, N.K. (Folder 17)
    - Vlasievskii, M.F., Oct. 1924
  - Sobolev, A. (Folder 18)
    - Sazonov, A.V., Dec. 1921
  - Sosnovskii, A.S.
    - Biskupskii, Dec. 1925 (Folder 19)
    - G.K., Dec. 1925 (Folder 20)
    - Kolesnikov, N.V., n.d. (Folder 21)
    - Moravskii, V.I., Sept. 1922-Sept. 1927 (Folder 22)
    - "Obshchestvo druzei gazety Rossiia," n.d. Rossiia, (letter to the editor), Dec. 1926 (Folder 23)
    - Semenov, G.M., n.d. (Folder 24)
    - Vasilii Vasilievich, Sept. 1925 (Folder 25)
    - Vasilii Vladimirovich, Dec. 1931 (Folder 26)
  - Stakhov, V.M. (Folder 27)
    - Moravskii, V.I., July 1930
  - Suganov, M. (Folder 28)
    - Moravskii, V.I., 1929
  - Svenson (Folder 29)
    - Moravskii, V.I., March 1925
  - Tsvetkov, S.I. (Folder 30)
    - Moravskii, V.I., Sept. 1934
  - Ungern, Baron (Folder 31)
    - Semenov, G.M., Jan. 1921
  - Vasiliev, B.P. (Folder 32)
    - Moravskii, V.I., Oct. 1922-Nov 1923
  - Vasiliev-Dubrovskii, A.N. (Folder 33)
    - Moravskii, V.I., March 1925-Sept. 1928
  - Vishnevskii, E.K. (Folder 34)
    - Sazonov, A.V., Sept. 1921-Jan. 1925
  - Vitkovskii, P.P. (Folder 35)
    - Moravskii, V.I., April 1934-March 1937
  - Vladislavtsev, I.V. (Folder 36)
    - Bretenar, V.V., Apr.-June 1933
    - Moravskii, V.I., Jan. 1932
  - Zaitsev, I.M. (Folder 37)
    - Cherednichenko-Mersie, V.P., Apr.-Aug. 1923
    - Sazonov, A.V., n.d.
  - Zenkevich, S.I. (Folder 38)
    - Moravskii, V.I., June-Nov. 1935
  - Zhemchiuzhyna, Z. (Folder 39)
    - Sazonov, A.V., n.d.
  - Zherbak (Folder 40)
    - Vasiliev, B.P., Nov. 1923
  - Zlatoustovskii,A. (Folder 41)
    - Sazonov, A.V., n.d.99 i
- Writings, 1927-1935
  Manuscripts, mostly on the history and politics of Siberia. Includes drafts of articles for Vol'naia Sibir'. Also includes excerpts from published (?) materials. Arranged alphabetically by author.
  - Manuscripts, n.d. (Box 10)
    - Anonymous
      - "K istorii Sibirkago Dvizheniia" (Folder 42)
      - "Sibirskie Oblastnye S"ezdy" (Folder 43)
      - "Vremennyii Sibirskii Sovet" (Folder 44)
    - Agapov, E.M., (drafts of articles for Nasha Gazeta) (Folder 45)
      - "Polustanok"
      - "Sibirskaia nelegal'naia organizatsiia"
    - Arskii, Maks, "Otkrytoe pis'mo k russkim liudiam," Dec. 1935 (Folder 46)
    - Dimitrievskii, S., "Stalin," n.d. (Folder 47)
    - Parfenov, P.S., "Uroki proshlago," n.d. (Folder 48)
    - Parfenov, P.S., "Uroki proshlago,"n.d. (Box 11, Folder l-2)
    - Russian, V.N., "Sovetskoe pravitel'stvo i mirovaia revoliutsiia," n.d. (Folder 3)
    - Sazonov, A.V., n.d. (Folder 4)
      - "Avtonomnaia Sibir'"
      - "Chto takoe bol'shevizm"
    - Z.N.P., "Siluety Iaponii," n.d. (Folder 5)
  - Vol'naia Sibir', drafts of articles, 1927-1928 (Folder 6-7)
- V.I. Moravskii Working Papers, n.d.
  Includes a short autobiography by V.I. Moravskii and biographical sketches of other members of the Council of Plenipotentiary Representatives of the Organizations of Autonomous Siberia found in the collection. Also includes explanatory notes by V.I. Moravskii and the original register compiled by him. Arranged by physical form.
  - Autobiographical data and personal reminiscences of the February and October Revolutions (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Explanatory notes on institutions mentioned in the documents (Folder 9)
  - Reminiscences of V.I. Moravskii and other biographical material
    - General. General D.L. Horvath. (Folder 10)
    - Great Britain. Includes material re General Graves and Mr. O'Reilly (Folder 11)
    - Japan. Includes material re Ronin Societies, Mitsuru Toyama, Generals Araki and Kudo (Folder 12)
  - Summaries of materials included in the collection. Prepared by V.I. Moravskii, n.d. (Folder 13)
  - Lists of material in the collection originally compiled by V.I. Moravskii, n.d.
    - l-200 (Folder 14)
    - 201-378 (Folder 15)
- Duplicates
  Duplicate copies of material found in other series. Unarranged.
  - Duplicate copies of material found in other series. Unarranged (Box 12-13.)
- Photographs
  - 51 miscellaneous prints, undated (Envelope A)
    Includes 12 postcard caricatures of members of the Maritime Parliamen; * Yenisei Okhrana file photos of Bolshevik revolutionaries, including F. Dzerzhinski, L. Kamanev, L. Krasin, V.I. Lenin, M. Litvinov, J. Stalin, L. Trotsky and G. Zinoviev; 2 prints of visit by Chiang Kai-shek to Soviet Consulate in Shanghai.
  - 11 prints of Japanese groups and individuals, undated (Envelope B)
    Includes portraits of Gen. Taga and Count Okuma.
  - 10 glass plates of documents found in the collection, undated (Box 14)